Hello English learners, welcome back to EnglishPod.
英语学习者你们好，欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erica.
我是Erica。
And today we have another romantic lesson, kind of romantic.
今天我们带来另一节浪漫的课程，有点浪漫。
A little romantic.
有点浪漫。
We got a boyfriend and a girlfriend and they're apologizing to each other.
我们有一对情侣，他们在互相道歉。
Okay, so it's a very common situation and we're going to be talking about love.
好的，这是一个非常常见的情景，我们将讨论爱情。
We're also going to talk about different pet names that are commonly used in English.
我们还会讨论英语中常用的不同爱称。
That are used with your boyfriend or girlfriend.
这些爱称用于你的男朋友或女朋友。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
So let's listen to this dialogue for the first time and see what's happening with our couple.
那么让我们第一次听这段对话，看看我们的情侣发生了什么。
Can we talk?
我们能谈谈吗？
You know what I mean.
你知道我的意思。
I want to know where this relationship is going.
我想知道这段关系会走向何方。
I'm in love with you and I need to know.
我爱上你了，我需要知道。
I'm awesome.
我很棒。
Well I guess that's my answer, isn't it?
好吧，我想这就是我的答案了，不是吗？
Look, if you don't love me, it's not a thing, alright?
听着，如果你不爱我，那没什么大不了的，好吗？
We've had our laughs, but I don't appreciate...
我们有过欢笑，但我不欣赏……
Maybe it's just time we...
也许我们该……
Baby, I love you so much.
宝贝，我非常爱你。
You do?
真的吗？
I love you and I think you're awesome.
我爱你，而且我觉得你很棒。
Oh, I love you too.
哦，我也爱你。
Come on, put the gun down.
来吧，把枪放下。
Oh baby, I'm so sorry.
哦宝贝，我很抱歉。
Okay, so romantic and dramatic.
好吧，既浪漫又戏剧化。
Yeah, I think she really needed to hear that shh.
是啊，我觉得她真的很需要听到那个嘘声。
Right, so I think she really wanted to hear I love you.
对，所以我觉得她真的很想听到“我爱你”。
Yeah, that's right.
是的，没错。
And there's some interesting phrases here in this dialogue and today we're going to
这段对话里有一些有趣的短语，今天我们主要关注短语。
focus mostly on phrases.
主要关注短语。
So why don't we start with Fluency Builder.
所以我们从流利度构建开始吧。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建。
Okay, on Fluency Builder today, we're going to take a look at some of these phrases and
好的，今天的流利度构建，我们来看看其中一些短语，第一个非常重要且非常不同。
the first one is very important and very different.
第一个非常重要且非常不同。
So obviously this dialogue is about love and we heard two different ways that this word
很明显这段对话是关于爱情的，我们听到了这个词的两种不同用法，第一种是爱某人。
is used and the first one is to love someone.
第一种是爱某人。
Right, so he said, I love you.
对，所以他说了“我爱你”。
Yeah, I love you.
是的，“我爱你”。
We all pretty much understand what that means.
我们基本都明白那是什么意思。
Right, but they also mentioned to be in love with someone.
对，但他们也提到了“爱上某人”。
Okay, so he said, I am in love with you.
好的，所以他说了“我爱上你了”。
I'm in love with you.
“我爱上你了”。
In love.
“爱上”。
Okay, so what's the difference between to love and to be in love?
好的，那么“爱”和“爱上”有什么区别？
To be in love with someone means that you have these strong romantic feelings towards
“爱上某人”意味着你对某人有强烈的浪漫感情。
somebody.
强烈的浪漫感情。
That's right.
没错。
So you can only be in love with your boyfriend, your girlfriend, your husband or your wife.
所以你只能爱上你的男朋友、女朋友、丈夫或妻子。
So you can love your parents, you can love your family, but you can't be in love with
所以你可以爱你的父母，爱你的家人，但你不能爱上他们。
them.
不能爱上他们。
You can only be in love with your girlfriend, boyfriend, husband, wife.
你只能爱上你的女朋友、男朋友、丈夫、妻子。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
So moving on to the next phrase.
那么继续下一个短语。
Now the girl asked her boyfriend, can we talk?
现在女孩问她的男朋友：“我们能谈谈吗？”
Can we talk?
“我们能谈谈吗？”
This is a very simple sentence.
这是一个非常简单的句子。
Right, we know the meaning, right?
对，我们知道意思，对吧？
But why does she say, can we talk?
但她为什么说“我们能谈谈”？
Okay, so you use this when you want to start a conversation about something serious.
好的，当你想要开始一个关于严肃话题的对话时，你会用这个。
Okay, so if you wanted to talk to me about my new shirt.
好的，所以如果你想跟我聊我的新衬衫。
I wouldn't ask, I wouldn't say, hey Marco, can we talk?
我不会问，我不会说：“嘿Marco，我们能谈谈吗？”
Oh, I really like your shirt.
哦，我真的很喜欢你的衬衫。
Where'd you get it?
你在哪儿买的？
Exactly, right?
正是，对吧？
It has to be serious.
必须是严肃的。
So usually if somebody says, hey, can we talk?
所以通常如果有人对你说：“嘿，我们能谈谈吗？”
It means that there's going to be a serious topic.
这意味着会有一个严肃的话题。
It's going to be probably bad news.
很可能是个坏消息。
Maybe bad news.
也许是坏消息。
So can we talk?
所以“我们能谈谈？”
So if your boyfriend or girlfriend tells you this, well, it's not a good sign.
所以如果你的男朋友或女朋友对你说这个，嗯，这不是个好兆头。
That's right.
没错。
All right.
好的。
And the last phrase that we have on Fluency Builder, you know what I mean.
流利度构建上的最后一个短语：“你知道我的意思。”
You know what I mean.
“你知道我的意思。”
All right.
好的。
So again, this phrase is very simple to understand, right?
所以再说一次，这个短语很容易理解，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
So you know what I'm talking about.
所以你知道我在说什么。
You understand me.
你理解我。
But the interesting thing is that we can also make it a question.
但有趣的是，我们也可以把它变成一个问句。
And it's all about the change in tone.
这完全取决于语调的变化。
Okay, so with this in mind, let's listen to two examples of the same phrase but with different
好的，那么记住这一点，让我们听两个相同短语但不同语调的例子，你试着看看哪个是问句。
tones and you try to see which one is the question.
你试着看看哪个是问句。
Example one.
例子一。
I'm tired of doing nothing all day here at home.
我整天在家无所事事，厌倦了。
You know what I mean?
你知道我的意思吗？
Example two.
例子二。
Come on, Charles.
拜托，Charles。
You know what I mean when I say that I don't like your friends.
当我说我不喜欢你的朋友时，你知道我的意思。
Example three.
例子三。
I hate this class.
我讨厌这门课。
It's so boring and tedious.
它又无聊又乏味。
You know what I mean?
你知道我的意思吗？
All right.
好的。
So we heard the examples and well, maybe you guessed it right.
所以我们听到了例子，嗯，也许你猜对了。
The second example was the question.
第二个例子是问句。
That's right.
没错。
You know what I mean?
“你知道我的意思？”
Right.
对。
So basically, you're asking the person if they understand your idea or they understand
所以基本上，你在问对方是否理解你的想法或你在说什么。
what you're talking about.
你在说什么。
So maybe you can say, the professor wasn't very clear on his instructions.
所以也许你可以说：“教授对指示说得不太清楚。”
So how was I supposed to do the homework?
“那我怎么做作业？”
You know what I mean?
“你知道我的意思吗？”
So you're asking me to confirm that I understand you.
所以你在让我确认我理解你。
My idea.
我的想法。
You understand what I'm saying?
你理解我在说什么吗？
Yeah.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
So you might say, hey, I don't like going to your mom's house.
所以你可以说：“嘿，我不喜欢去你妈妈家。”
So I would say, what?
那么我会说：“什么？”
What do you mean?
“你什么意思？”
Why?
“为什么？”
You know what I mean?
“你知道我的意思。”
Right.
对。
So I perfectly understand or know the reasons why you don't like going to my mom's house.
所以我完全理解或知道你为什么不喜欢去我妈妈家。
Like I don't have to tell you.
就像我不需要告诉你。
You know what I mean?
你知道我的意思。
All right.
好的。
Very good.
非常好。
So you know what I mean.
所以“你知道我的意思”。
Great.
太好了。
So we've taken a look at these four phrases.
所以我们看了这四个短语。
They're very simple, but the way that you use them gives them different meanings.
它们很简单，但使用方式赋予了它们不同的含义。
That's right.
没错。
All right.
好的。
So let's listen to our dialogue for the second time.
那么让我们第二次听我们的对话。
Just slow it down a little bit, and then we'll come back and look at some more phrases.
稍微放慢一点，然后我们回来再看一些短语。
Can we talk?
我们能谈谈吗？
Sure, honey.
当然，亲爱的。
We're talking now, aren't we?
我们现在就在谈，不是吗？
You know what I mean.
你知道我的意思。
Yeah, I know.
是的，我知道。
I want to know where this relationship is going.
我想知道这段关系会走向何方。
I'm in love with you, and I need to know...
我爱上你了，我需要知道……
You know, I think you're awesome.
你知道，我觉得你很棒。
I'm awesome.
我很棒。
Well, I guess that's my answer, isn't it?
好吧，我想这就是我的答案了，不是吗？
Honey.
亲爱的。
Look, if you don't love me, it's not a thing, all right?
听着，如果你不爱我，那没什么大不了的，好吗？
We've had our laughs, but I don't appreciate...
我们有过欢笑，但我不欣赏……
Maybe it's just time we...
也许我们该……
Baby, I love you so much.
宝贝，我非常爱你。
You do?
真的吗？
I love you, and I think you're awesome.
我爱你，而且我觉得你很棒。
Oh, I love you too.
哦，我也爱你。
Come on, put the gun down.
来吧，把枪放下。
Oh, baby, I'm so sorry.
哦宝贝，我很抱歉。
Okay, so now it's time for us to take a look at some more phrases, but this time we're
好的，现在是时候看看更多短语了，但这次我们要在“整合起来”中看它们。
going to look at them in putting it together.
整合起来。
Putting it together.
Okay, we're going to see how we can use these phrases in a few different situations.
好的，我们将看看如何在几种不同情况下使用这些短语。
So the girl wanted to talk to her boyfriend because she wanted to know where this relationship
所以女孩想和她的男朋友谈谈，因为她想知道这段关系会走向何方。
is going.
会走向何方。
Right.
对。
Where is this relationship going?
“这段关系会走向何方？”
So she wants to know what's going to happen or what's...
所以她想知道会发生什么或……
What's the future.
未来是什么。
What's the future of this relationship?
这段关系的未来是什么？
Are we going to get married?
我们会结婚吗？
Are we just...
还是我们只是……
What's happening?
发生了什么？
Yeah.
是的。
So why don't we listen to some examples with different nouns and how we can use this phrase?
那么为什么我们不听听一些不同名词的例子，以及我们如何使用这个短语？
Example one.
例子一。
I don't know where my career is going in this company.
我不知道在这家公司我的职业生涯会走向何方。
I don't see any potential for growth.
我看不到任何成长潜力。
Example two.
例子二。
This movie is so confusing.
这部电影太令人困惑了。
I have no idea where the plot is going.
我完全不知道情节会走向何方。
Example three.
例子三。
We have been in this meeting for over two hours and I still don't know where it's going.
这个会议已经开了两个多小时，我仍然不知道它会走向何方。
Okay, so again, this phrase is just asking about the future of something.
好的，所以再说一次，这个短语只是询问某事的未来。
Right.
对。
So where the future of this movie, where is this movie going?
所以这部电影的未来，这部电影会走向何方？
Yeah, what's happening?
是的，会发生什么？
Right.
对。
What's going to happen?
会发生什么？
Yeah.
是的。
Or your career, etc.
或者你的职业生涯等等。
Yeah.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
So, she was talking a little bit about her feelings and she said, maybe it's just time
所以，她谈了一点她的感受，她说：“也许我们该……”
we...
“也许我们该……”
Okay.
好的。
So this phrase isn't complete yet.
所以这个短语还不完整。
We need to finish it.
我们需要完成它。
Yeah.
是的。
But she is basically saying, maybe we should do this.
但她基本上是在说：“也许我们应该这样做。”
How can we finish the phrase?
我们如何完成这个短语？
All right.
好的。
So she could say, maybe it's just time we break up.
所以她可能会说，也许我们该分手了。
All right.
好吧。
Or I can say, maybe it's time we have a baby.
或者我可以说，也许我们该要个孩子了。
Oh, Marco.
哦，马可。
All right.
好吧。
And maybe it's time we go home.
也许我们该回家了。
Okay.
好的。
So it's getting late, let's go home.
所以时间不早了，我们回家吧。
Maybe it's time we go home.
也许我们该回家了。
Yeah.
是啊。
So this is how we can finish this phrase.
这就是我们如何结束这个短语。
And what about our last phrase?
那我们的最后一个短语呢？
So she also said, we've had our laps.
她还说，我们有过美好的时光。
Okay.
好的。
So that means we've had our good times.
所以那意味着我们有过好日子。
Yeah.
是啊。
Okay.
好的。
But we can change this to, we've had our ups and downs.
但我们可以改成，我们有过起起落落。
Okay.
好的。
Or we've had our moments.
或者我们有过我们的时刻。
Right.
对。
So that means we've had our good moments and our bad moments.
所以那意味着我们有过好时刻和坏时刻。
That's right.
没错。
Or we've had our issues.
或者我们有过我们的问题。
Okay.
好的。
So that means we've had some problems.
所以那意味着我们有过一些麻烦。
We've had some difficulties.
我们有过一些困难。
Or even we've had our moments.
或者甚至是我们有过我们的时刻。
Okay.
好的。
So that means we've had...
所以那意味着我们有过……
Special times.
特别的时光。
So that means we've had our special times, special occasions that we will always remember.
所以那意味着我们有过特别的时光、特别的日子，我们会永远记住。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
So three really useful structures that you can change the words a little bit to slightly
所以三个非常有用的结构，你可以稍微改一下词来略微
change the meaning.
改变意思。
Okay.
好的。
So it's time for us to listen to our dialogue for the last time.
所以是时候让我们最后一次听对话了。
Now we're ready to understand everything.
现在我们准备好理解一切了。
And then we'll come back and give you some examples of pet names in English.
然后我们会回来给你们一些英语中爱称的例子。
Can we talk?
我们能谈谈吗？
You know what I mean.
你懂我的意思。
I want to know where this relationship is going.
我想知道这段关系会走向何方。
I'm in love with you and I need to know...
我爱上你了，我需要知道……
I'm awesome.
我很棒。
Well, I guess that's my answer, isn't it?
嗯，我想那就是我的答案了，对吧？
Look, if you don't love me, it's not a thing.
听着，如果你不爱我，那也没关系。
All right.
好吧。
We've had our laughs, but I don't appreciate...
我们有过欢笑，但我不欣赏……
Maybe it's just time we...
也许我们该……
Baby, I love you so much.
宝贝，我太爱你了。
You do?
真的吗？
I love you and I think you're awesome.
我爱你，而且我觉得你很棒。
Oh, I love you too.
哦，我也爱你。
Come on, put the gun down.
来吧，把枪放下。
Oh, baby.
哦，宝贝。
I'm so sorry.
我很抱歉。
All right.
好吧。
Well, Marco, you mentioned this word pet names.
嗯，马可，你提到了“爱称”这个词。
And what exactly is that?
那到底是什么？
All right.
好吧。
So pet names aren't names for your dogs or your cats.
所以爱称不是给你的狗或猫起的名字。
Okay.
好的。
Right.
对。
So pet names that you would call your boyfriend or girlfriend.
所以爱称是你用来称呼男朋友或女朋友的。
Okay.
好的。
So like baby.
比如“宝贝”。
Okay.
好的。
In our dialogue, we heard baby.
在我们的对话中，我们听到了“宝贝”。
Yeah.
是啊。
Right?
对吧？
So we're not talking about a little...
所以我们不是在说一个小……
A little child.
一个小孩子。
No.
不是。
This is usually how you would call maybe your girlfriend or boyfriend, baby.
这通常是你用来称呼女朋友或男朋友的方式，“宝贝”。
Or honey.
或者“亲爱的”。
Honey.
“亲爱的”。
Right.
对。
Hey, honey.
嘿，亲爱的。
Or honey, I'm home.
或者亲爱的，我回来了。
Yeah.
是啊。
Right.
对。
But we also have other ones like sweetheart or...
但我们还有其他的，比如“甜心”或……
Darling.
“亲爱的”。
Yeah.
是啊。
Or what about sweetie or cutie?
那“甜心”或“小可爱”呢？
Cutie.
“小可爱”。
Oh.
哦。
Yeah.
是啊。
I think these phrases can be a little bit like cheesy maybe.
我觉得这些短语可能有点俗气。
Yeah.
是啊。
A little too sweet.
有点太甜了。
Too much.
太过头了。
Yeah.
是啊。
Like snookums.
比如“小甜心”。
Snookums.
“小甜心”。
Like snookums.
比如“小甜心”。
Okay.
好的。
Or honey bunny.
或者“蜜兔”。
Oh, yeah.
哦，是啊。
Yeah.
是啊。
You also have sweetie pie.
你还有“甜心派”。
Yeah.
是啊。
And some of them will make some up, right?
有些人还会自己编一些，对吧？
Maybe they'll call their boyfriend poo bear.
也许他们会叫男朋友“小熊”。
Oh, yeah.
哦，是啊。
Right?
对吧？
Yeah.
是啊。
Like Winnie the Pooh, poo bear.
就像小熊维尼，“小熊”。
I heard dumpling is a common one.
我听说“小团子”是一个常见的。
Yeah.
是啊。
So, you can make up your own pet names, right?
所以，你可以自己编爱称，对吧？
Yeah.
是啊。
So, I want to hear from our listeners.
所以，我想听听听众们的意见。
Are there any common pet names in your language?
在你们的语言中有常见的爱称吗？
I know that in Spanish, we can sometimes call our girlfriend gorda, which actually means
我知道在西班牙语里，我们有时会叫女朋友“gorda”，这实际上意思是
fat.
“胖”。
But it's not in a bad way.
但这不是贬义的。
Really?
真的吗？
It's a sweet way of calling your girlfriend.
这是一种甜蜜的方式称呼女朋友。
And I know in French, you can say ma pouce, which basically means my flea.
我知道在法语里，你可以说“ma pouce”，基本上意思是“我的小跳蚤”。
Yeah.
是啊。
So, some of them, if you translate, you wouldn't really use in English.
所以，有些词如果直译，在英语里不会真的用。
But let us know.
但请告诉我们。
Translate from your language or other ones that you've heard maybe in movies or talk
从你的语言里翻译过来，或者你在电影或脱口秀里听过的其他词。
shows.
脱口秀。
And come to our website, EnglishPod.com.
然后来我们的网站，EnglishPod.com。
Yeah.
是啊。
Leave your questions there as well as your pet names.
在那里留下你的问题，还有你的爱称。
And Marco and I are always happy to see you there.
马可和我总是很高兴在那里见到你。
Okay.
好的。
Until next time.
下次再见。
Goodbye.
再见。
Bye.
拜拜。